Register of the Milan Gavrilović Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence, 1941-1975 (Box 3-19, Reel 3-22)
  - Mihailović, Peter D., 1945 (Reel 14, Box-folder 12: 11)
  - Mihajlović, Uglješa, 1967 (Reel 14, Box-folder 12: 12)
  - Mihaldzić, 1946 (Reel 14, Box-folder 12: 13)
  - Mijović, Vujadin Mil., 1958 (Reel 14, Box-folder 12: 14)
  - Mikołajczyk, Stanisław, 1943-1963 (Reel 14, Box-folder 12: 15)
  - Milanov, Kajica, 1951 (Reel 14, Box-folder 12: 16)
  - Milčić, Božidar, 1964 (Reel 14, Box-folder 12: 17)
  - Milenković, Stojadin (Club Culturel National Serbe en Suisse, Berne), 1962-1969 (Box-folder 12: 18, Reel 14)
  - Miletich, Branko S., 1953-1957 (Box-folder 12: 19, Reel 14)
  - Miletić, Vukadin, 1941-1961 (Box-folder 12: 20, Reel 14)
  - Milojković, Stevan, 1955 (Box-folder 12: 21, Reel 14)
  - Milosavljević, Petar M., 1962-1974 (Box-folder 12: 22, Reel 14)
  - Milovanović, Mileta (Serb National Federation), 1961-1962 (Box-folder 12: 23, Reel 14)
  - Milovanović, Milovan, 1911 (Box-folder 12: 24, Reel 14)
  - Minić, Mihailo, 1966 (Box-folder 12: 25, Reel 14)
  - Miodrag, Miloš, 1961-1962 (Reel 14, Box-folder 12: 26)
  - Mirković, Voja, 1961-1968 (Reel 14, Box-folder 12: 27)
  - Mirošević-Sorgo, Niko, 1957-1961 (Reel 14, Box-folder 12: 28)
  - Mitchell, Harold, 1942-1943 (Reel 14, Box-folder 12: 29)
  - Mitich, Drag (The American Association of War Veterans of the Former Kingdom of Yugoslavia), 1967 (Reel 14, Box-folder 12: 30)
  - Mitrović, Milosav, 1947-1963 (Reel 14, Box-folder 12: 31)
  - Mitrović, N., 1953 (Reel 14, Box-folder 12: 32)
  - Mitrović, Predrag, 1963 (Reel 14, Box-folder 12: 33)
  - Mogan, Nikola, 1942 (Reel 14, Box-folder 12: 34)
  - Munjić, Dimitrije, 1974 (Box-folder 12: 35, Reel 14)
  - Mutavdzich, Dobrivoy (Mutavdzic, Dobrivoje), 1968-1969 (Box-folder 12: 36, Reel 14)
  - Narodni Ravnogorski Pokret za Ameriku, 1954 (Box-folder 12: 37, Reel 14)
  - Niciforović, Stevan, 1967-1972 (Box-folder 12: 38, Reel 14)
  - Niemeyer, Gerhart, 1955 (Box-folder 12: 39, Reel 14)
  - Nikiforov, Maria, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 12: 40, Reel 14)
  - Nikodijević, Dragiša, 1961 (Box-folder 12: 41, Reel 14)
  - Nikolić, Jovan P., 1973 (Box-folder 12: 42, Reel 14)
  - Nikolić, Miloje (Archpriest of the Serbian Orthodox Church of St. Sava, London), 1948-1974 (Reel 14, Box-folder 12: 43)
  - Njegoš, Srpsko istorijsko-kulturno drustvo (Serbian Historical and Cultural Society), 1959-1974 (Reel 14, Box-folder 12: 44)
  - Novak, Milan, 1945 (Reel 14, Box-folder 12: 45)
  - Novaković, A., 1918 (Reel 14, Box-folder 12: 46)
  - Novoye Russkoye Slovo, 1956 (Box-folder 12: 47, Reel 14)
  - Obradović, Milan, 1946 (Box-folder 12: 48, Reel 14)
  - Ocko-Forcan, B. M., 1973 (Reel 14, Box-folder 12: 49)
  - Orelj, Ilija (Veterans of General Draza Mihailovic "Ravna Gora" Movement of America), 1952-1953 (Reel 14, Box-folder 12: 50)
  - Ost-Europa, 1948 (Box-folder 12: 51, Reel 14)
  - Osusky, Stefan, 1943 (Box-folder 12: 52, Reel 14)
  - Overseas Press Club of America, 1952 (Box-folder 12: 53, Reel 14)
  - Oxford University Masaryk Society (Wheeler, Mary), 1942 (Folder 12: 54)
  - Paget, Leila, Lady (Box 13)
    - 1947-1952 (Reel 15, Box-folder 13: 1)
    - 1953-1954 (Box-folder 13: 2, Reel 15)
    - 1955 (Box-folder 13: 3, Reel 15)
    - 1956 (Reel 15, Box-folder 13: 4)
    - 1957-1958 (Reel 15, Box-folder 13: 5)
  - Pajcic, Ljubomir J., 1962 (Reel 16, Box-folder 13: 6)
  - Panin, Ester, 1953 (Reel 16, Box-folder 13: 7)
  - Pantelić, Vojislav D., 1963-1974 (Box-folder 13: 8, Reel 16)
  - Paranos, Vasilije, 1951 (Reel 16, Box-folder 13: 9)
  - Parežanin, Ratko, 1947 (Box-folder 13: 10, Reel 16)
  - Pašić, Nikola, 1956 (Reel 16, Box-folder 13: 11)
  - Paunović, Jovan, 1958-1963 (Box-folder 13: 12, Reel 16)
  - Paunović, S., 1942 (Box-folder 13: 13, Reel 16)
  - Pavelić, Ante Smith, 1958 (Box-folder 14: 1, Reel 16)
  - Pavičević, Miloš, 1973 (Box-folder 14: 2, Reel 16)
  - Pavlović, Ilija, 1967-1975 (Box-folder 14: 3, Reel 16)
  - Pavlović, Milija, 1947 (Reel 16, Box-folder 14: 4)
  - Pavlovich, George, 1960 (Box-folder 14: 5, Reel 16)
  - Pavlowitch (Pavlović), Kosta St., 1946-1975 (Reel 16, Box-folder 14: 6)
  - Pažarac, Sim. D., 1953 (Reel 16, Box-folder 14: 7)
  - Pejovic, L. M. (Peyovich), 1959-1961 (Reel 16, Box-folder 14: 8)
  - Penkala, Eduard, 1946 (Reel 16, Box-folder 14: 9)
  - Pennsylvania College for Women, 1951 (Box-folder 14: 10, Reel 16)
  - Pepić, Boža, 1952-1960 (Box-folder 14: 11, Reel 16)
  - Pepić, Branko, 1942-1947 (Reel 16, Box-folder 14: 12)
  - Perić, Velibor R., 1962 (Reel 16, Box-folder 14: 13)
  - Perisic, Aleksander
    - 1953-1958 (Reel 16, Box-folder 14: 14)
    - 1959-1961 (Box-folder 14: 15, Reel 16)
    - 1962-1971 (Box-folder 14: 16, Reel 16)
  - Perović, Miladin R., 1952-1970 (Box-folder 14: 17, Reel 16)
  - Pešelj, Branko, 1960 (Box-folder 14: 18, Reel 16)
  - Petković, Dušan, 1963-1974 (Box-folder 14: 19, Reel 17)
  - Petković, Vlasta, 1945-1965 (Reel 17, Box-folder 14: 20)
  - Petrov, Vladimir, 1966 (Reel 17, Box-folder 14: 21)
  - Petrović, Bora, 1974 (Reel 17, Box-folder 14: 22)
  - Petrović, Dragoljub, 1948 (Reel 17, Box-folder 14: 23)
  - Petrović, Mihajlo, n.d. (Reel 17, Box-folder 14: 24)
  - Petrović, Svetislav, 1956 (Reel 17, Box-folder 14: 25)
  - Pickthorn, K. H., 1948 (Reel 17, Box-folder 14: 26)
  - Piletić, Velimir, 1966-1971 (Reel 17, Box-folder 14: 27)
  - Plamenac, Ilija P., 1941-1948 (Reel 17, Box-folder 14: 28)
  - Plamenac, Jovo, n.d. (Reel 17, Box-folder 14: 29)
  - Pocerac, 1951 (Reel 17, Box-folder 14: 30)
  - Pokret Srpskih Četnika "Ravna Gora,", 1961 (Box-folder 14: 31, Reel 17)
  - Politis, Athanase G., 1951 (Box-folder 14: 32, Reel 17)
  - Popović, Borislav,., 1951-1975 (Box-folder 15: 1, Reel 17)
    Includes asylum request of 1950
  - Popović, Dragan, 1942-1958 (Box-folder 15: 2, Reel 17)
  - Popović, Jovan, 1948-1950 (Box-folder 15: 3, Reel 17)
  - Popović, Novica, 1960 (Box-folder 15: 4, Reel 17)
  - Popović, Radomir, 1946 (Reel 17, Box-folder 15: 5)
  - Predavac, Vladimir, 1946 (Reel 17, Box-folder 15: 6)
  - Pribičević, Adam, 1946-1952 (Reel 17, Box-folder 15: 7)
  - Protić, 1956-1958 (Reel 17, Box-folder 15: 8)
  - Pukić, 1951 (Reel 17, Box-folder 15: 9)
  - Purić, Božidar (Prime Minister, Royal Yugoslav Government), 1948 (Reel 17, Box-folder 15: 10)
  - Purić, Mihailo and Frances, 1951-1952 (Reel 17, Box-folder 15: 11)
  - Purić (Pouritch), Milan, 1945-1964 (Reel 17, Box-folder 15: 12)
  - Purković, Miodrag, 1959-1962 (Reel 17, Box-folder 15: 13)
  - Radičević, S., 1959 (Reel 17, Box-folder 15: 14)
  - Radio Free Europe, 1972 (Reel 17, Box-folder 15: 15)
  - Radojevich, Djuro M. (Serbian National Committee), 1960-1975 (Reel 18, Box-folder 15: 16)
  - Radonjić, Savo, 1958-1963 (Reel 18, Box-folder 15: 17)
  - Radovančev, Radislav, 1948-1973 (Reel 18, Box-folder 15: 18)
  - Radović, Veljko Rad., 1973 (Reel 18, Box-folder 15: 19)
  - Radović, Vukosav, 1950 (Reel 18, Box-folder 15: 20)
  - Raikes, Victor, 1945 (Reel 18, Box-folder 15: 21)
  - Rajić, Milorad M., 1964 (Reel 18, Box-folder 15: 22)
  - Rajković, Mihailo F., n.d. (Box-folder 15: 23, Reel 18)
  - Rajnović, Nikola, 1961 (Box-folder 15: 24, Reel 18)
  - Ralević, Niko, 1955-1975 (Box-folder 15: 25, Reel 18)
  - Rapajich, Djordje G1iša, 1966 (Box-folder 16: 1, Reel 18)
  - Rašević, Veljko, 1950 (Box-folder 16: 2, Reel 18)
  - Rašić, S., 1947 (Box-folder 16: 3, Reel 18)
  - Rašić, Zlatko, 1952 (Box-folder 16: 4, Reel 18)
  - Rašković, Dragan B., n.d. (Box-folder 16: 5, Reel 18)
  - Ravnogorski Narodni Pokret u Francuskoj, 1948 (Reel 18, Box-folder 16: 6)
  - Refugees Defense Committee, 1948 (Reel 18, Box-folder 16: 7)
  - Rendel, George, Sir (British Ambassador to the Royal Yugoslav Government in London), 1942-1943 (Reel 18, Box-folder 16: 8)
  - Retinger, J. H. (Joint International Committee of Movements for European Unity), 1948 (Reel 18, Box-folder 16: 9)
  - Rhonda, Margaret Haig Thomas, Viscountess, 1943 (Reel 18, Box-folder 16: 10)
  - Ristić, Dragiša, 1957-1961 (Reel 18, Box-folder 16: 11)
  - Robinson, Vandeleur, 1943-1948 (Reel 18, Box-folder 16: 12)
  - Ronac, 1960 (Reel 18, Box-folder 16: 13)
  - Royal Institute of International Affairs, 1942-1944 (Reel 18, Box-folder 16: 14)
  - Russell, E. John, 1942-1943 (Reel 18, Box-folder 16: 15)
  - Ružić, Jevto A., 1969 (Box-folder 16: 16, Reel 18)
  - St. Luke Serbian Eastern Orthodox Church (Srpska istočno pravoslavna crkva Svetog Luke), 1968-1974 (Box-folder 16: 17, Reel 18)
  - Šajković, Ivan S., 1941 (Box-folder 16: 18, Reel 18)
  - Salata, Petar, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 16: 19, Reel 18)
  - Savadinović, Živko, 1953 (Box-folder 16: 20, Reel 18)
  - Savić, Milutin, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 16: 21, Reel 18)
  - Savić, R., 1966 (Box-folder 16: 22, Reel 18)
  - Savić, S., 1962 (Box-folder 16: 23, Reel 18)
  - Savić, Svetislav, 1948 (Reel 18, Box-folder 16: 24)
  - Scottish League for European Freedom, 1946 (Reel 18, Box-folder 16: 25)
  - Sedlar, Dušan M., n.d. (Reel 18, Box-folder 16: 26)
  - Seferović, Uroš, 1960-1967 (Reel 18, Box-folder 16: 27)
  - Segal, Jerry, 1965 (Reel 18, Box-folder 16: 28)
  - Seitz, A., Mrs., n.d. (Reel 18, Box-folder 16: 29)
  - Sekulić, Miloš, 1942-1971 (Reel 18, Box-folder 16: 30)
  - Serbian National Defense Council of America
    - General, 1947-1975 (Reel 18, Box-folder 16: 31)
    - Aliquippa Chapter, 1961 (Reel 19, Box-folder 16: 32)
    - Cleveland Chapter, 1972 (Reel 19, Box-folder 16: 33)
    - "Draža Mihailović" Branch Long Island, New York, 1967 (Box-folder 16: 34, Reel 19)
    - New York Chapter, 1964 (Box-folder 16: 35, Reel 19)
    - Youngstown-Ohio Chapter, 1960 (Box-folder 16: 36, Reel 19)
  - Šešlija, Risto G., 1959 (Box-folder 16: 37, Reel 19)
  - Seton-Watson, R. W., n.d. (Box-folder 16: 38, Reel 19)
  - Shijachki, Milan D., 1970 (Box-folder 16: 39, Reel 19)
  - Shillan, Mr., 1943 (Reel 19, Box-folder 16: 40)
  - Shoup, Dick, 1971 (Reel 19, Box-folder 16: 41)
  - Šikuljak, Simo O., 1969 (Reel 19, Box-folder 16: 42)
  - Šiljegović, Vladimir, 1950-1951 (Reel 19, Box-folder 16: 43)
  - Sirc, Ljubo, 1958 (Reel 19, Box-folder 16: 44)
  - Sloga, 1952-1956 (Reel 19, Box-folder 16: 45)
  - Small, Mr. and Mrs., 1942-1943 (Box-folder 16: 46, Reel 19)
  - Smiljanić, Milivoje D. (Assistant Foreign Minister until April 1941 and Minister to Cairo during World War II), 1940-1944 (Reel 19, Box-folder 16: 47)
  - Snoj, Franc, 1942 (Reel 19, Box-folder 16: 48)
  - Sokołowski, M., 1949-1950 (Reel 19, Box-folder 16: 49)
  - Soumar, Robert B., 1956 (Box-folder 16: 50, Reel 19)
  - Soviet War News, n.d. (Box-folder 16: 51, Reel 19)
  - Spasić, Branko, 1948 (Box-folder 16: 52, Reel 19)
  - Spasojević, Velimir, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 16: 53, Reel 19)
  - Spindler, Dr. (and Mr. Krajnc), 1946 (Box-folder 16: 54, Reel 19)
  - Srbakov, Stefan M., 1955 (Reel 19, Box-folder 16: 55)
  - Srpska bratska pomoć (Serbian Brothers' Help), 1961-1975 (Box-folder 16: 56, Reel 19)
  - Srpska narodna odbrana u Kanadi (Serbian National Shield Society of Canada), 1955-1961 (Box-folder 16: 57, Reel 19)
  - Srpska pravoslavna crkvena opština Sv. Save u Beču (Serbische Griechisch-Orientalische Kirchengemeinde zum Hl. Sava in Wien), 1968 (Reel 19, Box-folder 16: 58)
  - Srpska pravoslavna crkvena opština u Osnabrück-u, 1966 (Reel 19, Box-folder 16: 59)
  - Srpska pravoslavna crkvena zajednica za Nemačku (Kirchengemeinschaft für Deutschland, Kotur, Krstivoj), 1947 (Reel 19, Box-folder 16: 60)
  - Srpski narodni univerzitet (Serbian People's University), 1958-1974 (Reel 19, Box-folder 16: 61)
  - Stakic, Vladislav D., 1947-1948 (Box-folder 17: 1, Reel 19)
  - Stamenitch, Zlatan, 1954-1960 (Box-folder 17: 2, Reel 19)
  - Stanić, Milinko, 1948 (Box-folder 17: 3, Reel 19)
  - Stanisavljević, Vladislav, 1948 (Box-folder 17: 4, Reel 19)
  - Stanišić, Miomir M., 1962-1973 (Reel 19, Box-folder 17: 5)
  - Staniszewski, Kazimir, 1956 (Reel 19, Box-folder 17: 6)
  - Stanković, Mina, 1971-1972 (Reel 19, Box-folder 17: 7)
  - Stanković, Ratomir Čedomira, 1945 (Box-folder 17: 8, Reel 19)
  - Stanojlović, Božidar, 1959 (Box-folder 17: 9, Reel 19)
  - Stepanovich, Nick T., 1971 (Box-folder 17: 10, Reel 19)
  - Stevens, Doris, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 17: 11, Reel 19)
  - Stojanović, Milan, 1972 (Box-folder 17: 12, Reel 19)
  - Stojanović, Stojadin, 1960-1963 (Reel 19, Box-folder 17: 13)
  - Stojanović, Vlasta, 1971 (Reel 19, Box-folder 17: 14)
  - Stojsic, Lazar, 1967-1971 (Reel 19, Box-folder 17: 15)
  - Stoyanovitch, V. P., 1960 (Reel 19, Box-folder 17: 16)
  - Šuljak, Dinko, 1963 (Box-folder 17: 17, Reel 19)
  - Šumenković (Choumenkovitch), Ilija (Yugoslav Ambassador to Turkey), 1942-1951 (Box-folder 17: 18, Reel 19)
  - Šumenković (Choumenkovitch), Milorad I., 1947 (Box-folder 17: 19, Reel 19)
  - Šusović, Perovan, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 17: 20, Reel 19)
  - Šutej, Juraj, 1942 (Reel 19, Box-folder 17: 21)
  - Tašković, Gligo, 1948-1954 (Reel 19, Box-folder 17: 22)
  - Tašković, Ljubo, 1948 (Reel 19, Box-folder 17: 23)
  - Tešanović, Uroš, 1960 (Reel 19, Box-folder 17: 24)
  - Testimonial Committee, 1955 (Box-folder 17: 25, Reel 19)
  - Thomas, Ivor, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 17: 26, Reel 19)
  - Tilea, Viorel V., 1942-1943 (Box-folder 17: 27, Reel 19)
  - Todorov, Kosta, n.d. (Box-folder 17: 28, Reel 19)
  - Tomovich, Anthony M., 1960-1968 (Reel 19, Box-folder 17: 29)
  - Topalović, Tihomir, 1967 (Reel 20, Box-folder 17: 30)
  - Topalović, Živko (President of the Serbian Socialist Party), 1945-1956 (Reel 20, Box-folder 17: 31)
  - Trifković, Borislav and Ognjana
    - Undated (Reel 20, Box-folder 17: 32)
    - 1948-1959 (Box-folder 17: 33, Reel 20)
    - 1960-1968 (Box-folder 17: 34, Reel 20)
  - Trifković, Vasa L., 1970 (Box-folder 18: 1, Reel 20)
  - Trivunac, Stevan, 1945-1968 (Box-folder 18: 2, Reel 20)
  - Trklja, Risto, 1950-1969 (Reel 20, Box-folder 18: 3)
  - Tupanjanin, Miloš, 1948-1967 (Box-folder 18: 4, Reel 20)
  - Udruženje Boraca Jugoslovenske Vojske u Otadžbini, 1946 (Reel 21, Folder-box 18: 5)
  - Udruženje Srpskih pisaca i umetnika u inostranstvu (Society of Serbian Writers and Artists Abroad), 1953-1974 (Reel 21, Box-folder 18: 6)
  - Ujedinjena Demokratska Omladina Jugoslavije, 1945 (Reel 21, Box-folder 18: 7)
  - United States. Department of State, 1950 (Reel 21, Box-folder 18: 8)
  - Urošević, Miodrag, 1948-1973 (Box-folder 18: 9, Reel 21)
  - Vansittart, Lord, 1945 (Box-folder 18: 10, Reel 21)
  - Varga, Bela (Hungarian National Council), 1955 (Box-folder 18: 11, Reel 21)
  - Vaughan, A., 1947 (Box-folder 18: 12, Reel 21)
  - Velikov, Vladimir, 1974 (Reel 21, Box-folder 18: 13)
  - Velimirović, Nikolai, Bishop, 1945-1946 (Reel 21, Box-folder 18: 14)
  - Vidmavić, Milena Seka, 1966 (Box-folder 18: 15, Reel 21)
  - Vitov, Maurice, 1945 (Box-folder 18: 16, Reel 21)
  - Vlahović, Milorad M., 1955-1973 (Box-folder 18: 17, Reel 21)
  - Vlahović, Mirko M., 1967-1968 (Box-folder 18: 18, Reel 21)
  - Vlajić, Božidar, 1953-1960 (Box-folder 18: 19, Reel 21)
  - Vlajić, Ljubomir V., 1948 (Reel 21, Box-folder 18: 20)
  - Voigt, F. A. ( Nineteenth Century and After), 1942-1946 (Reel 21, Box-folder 18: 21)
  - Vojnović, Radislav, 1970 (Reel 21, Box-folder 18: 22)
  - Vosnjak, Bogumil, 1956 (Box-folder 18: 23, Reel 21)
  - Vračarević, Boško, 1957-1960 (Box-folder 18: 24, Reel 21)
  - Vranjašević, Vladimir, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 18: 25, Reel 21)
  - Vuceljić, Novak, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 18: 26, Reel 21)
  - Vučetić, Mato, 1957 (Box-folder 18: 27, Reel 21)
  - Vučković, Vojislav, 1944 (Box-folder 18: 28, Reel 21)
  - Vucurević, Petar, n.d. (Box-folder 18: 29, Reel 21)
  - Vukcević, Radoje, 1959-1966 (Box-folder 18: 30, Reel 21)
  - Vukelić, Djuro, 1969 (Box-folder 18: 31, Reel 21)
  - Vukobratović, Mane, 1945-1948 (Box-folder 18: 32, Reel 21)
  - Vuković, Miodrag M., 1974 (Box-folder 18: 33, Reel 21)
  - Vulović, Miljko, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 18: 34, Reel 21)
  - Vurdelja, Dragoljub, 1945-1971 (Reel 21, Box-folder 18: 35)
  - West, Rebecca, 1942-1968 (Record-cabinet 21, Box-folder 18: 36)
  - Weyemberg, P., 1943 (Reel 21, Box-folder 18: 37)
  - Wheeldon, Rita, 1946 (Reel 21, Box-folder 18: 38)
  - Whyte, Frederick, 1942 (Box-folder 18: 39, Reel 21)
  - Wilk, Franciszek (Polish Populist Party), 1968-1975 (Box-folder 19: 1, Reel 21)
  - Workers' Educational Association, 1943 (Box-folder 19: 2, Reel 21)
  - Yefremovich, Spasa, 1942-1971 (Box-folder 19: 3, Reel 21)
  - Yovanovich, J. M., 1948 (Box-folder 19: 4, Reel 21)
  - Zanella, P., 1958 (Box-folder 19: 5, Reel 21)
  - Zarić, Bogdan, 1956-1975 (Box-folder 19: 6, Reel 21)
  - Zelen, Todor M., 1966 (Box-folder 19: 7, Reel 21)
  - Zdravković, Dragiša
    - 1952-1964 (Box-folder 19: 8, Reel 21)
    - 1965-1975 (Box-folder 19: 9, Reel 21)
  - Zečević, Kristofor, 1949 (Box-folder 19: 10, Reel 22)
  - Zečević, Vladimir and others, 1949 (Box-folder 19: 11, Reel 22)
  - Želalić, Špiro, 1952-1956 (Box-folder 19: 12, Reel 22)
  - Zemaljski odbor Narodne radikalne stranke za Ameriku, 1963-1973 (Box-folder 19: 13, Reel 22)
  - Zikich, Dobrivoje, 1966-1968 (Reel 22, Box-folder 19: 14)
  - Zindović, Ratko, 1959-1962 (Reel 22, Box-folder 19: 15)
  - Živanović, Dragan, 1952 (Reel 22, Box-folder 19: 16)
  - Živković, Sima, 1943 (Box-folder 19: 17, Reel 22)
  - Zlatoper, Grga, 1951 (Box-folder 19: 18, Reel 22)
  - Zotović, Dragomir, 1967 (Box-folder 19: 19, Reel 22)
  - Zugić, Branislav, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 19: 20, Reel 22)
  - Žujović, Mladen, 1943-1948 (Box-folder 19: 21, Reel 22)
  - Zunich, Mitchell, 1963 (Box-folder 19: 22, Reel 22)
- Speeches and Writings,., 1947-1979 (Box 19-30, Reel 21-38)
  Handwritten, typewritten, and printed copies of speeches and writings by Milan Gavrilović. Arranged chronologically by title
  - General
    - General
      - Drafts and notes (Box-folder 19: 23-24, Reel 22)
      - Drafts and notes (Reel 22-24, Box-folder 20: 1-6)
      - Drafts and notes (Box-folder 21: 1-5, Reel 24-26)
      - Drafts and notes (Box-folder 22: 1-7, Reel 26-27)
      - Drafts and notes (Reel 28, Box-folder 23: 1-4)
      - Fragments of drafts for unidentifiable speeches and writings (Reel 29, Box-folder 23: 5-6)
      - Fragments of drafts for unidentifiable speeches and writings (Box-folder 24: 1-3, Reel 29-30)
    - Undated (Box-folder 24: 4-7, Reel 30)
    - Undated (Folder 25: 1-6, Reel 30-32)
    - Undated (Reel 32-33, Box-folder 26: 1-5)
    - 1952-1961 (Reel 33, Box-folder 26: 6)
    - 1962 (Box-folder 26: 7, Reel 33)
    - 1963-1972 (Box-folder 26: 8, Reel 33)
  - ",", 1389-1941 n.d. (Box-folder 27: 1, Reel 33)
    Typescript (in Serbo-Croatian)
  - "Agriculture,", n.d. (Box-folder 27: 2, Reel 33)
    Typescript
  - "Alarm, But Not Panic,", n.d. (Box-folder 27: 3, Reel 33)
  - "Berlin,", n.d. (Box-folder 27: 4, Reel 33)
  - "Bogumil Vošnjak,", n.d. (Reel 33, Box-folder 27: 5)
  - "Čardak Ni Na Nebu Ni Na Zemlji,", n.d. (Box-folder 27: 6, Reel 33)
  - "Dr. Zhivago,", n.d. (Reel 33, Box-folder 27: 7)
    Holograph and typescript (in English)
  - "Faraonska Politika,", n.d. (Reel 33, Box-folder 27: 8)
  - "Finansiska Pomoć Titu,", n.d. (Reel 33, Box-folder 27: 9)
  - "The Great Santa Claus,", n.d. (Reel 33, Box-folder 27: 10)
  - "Hungarian Peasants,", n.d. (Reel 33, Box-folder 27: 11)
  - "Intervju sa Dr. M. Gavrilovicem,", n.d. (Reel 34, Box-folder 27: 12)
  - "Koijim Putem?", n.d. (Reel 34, Box-folder 27: 13)
  - "Konstantin Fotić,", n.d. (Reel 34, Box-folder 27: 14)
  - "Kruščevljeva Fantasnagoria,", n.d. (Box-folder 27: 15, Reel 34)
  - "Labudova Pesma,", n.d. (Box-folder 27: 16, Reel 34)
  - "Memento Mori,", n.d. (Box-folder 27: 17, Reel 34)
  - Memoirs (excerpts), n.d. (Box-folder 27: 18, Reel 34)
    (partially in Serbo-Croatian)
  - "Miloš Acin Kosta: Zamrznute Vatre,", n.d. (Box-folder 27: 19, Reel 34)
  - "Mr. Khrushchev and a 'Good Piece of Meat'," (Box-folder 27: 20, Reel 34)
  - "Na Raskrsnici,", n.d. (Box-folder 27: 21, Reel 34)
  - "On the Failure of Collective Agriculture,", n.d. (Reel 34, Box-folder 27: 22)
  - "Peasant Parties,", n.d. (Reel 34, Box-folder 27: 23)
  - "Policy of the West,", n.d. (Reel 34, Box-folder 27: 24)
  - "Pregled Opsteg Polozaja Jugoslavije,", n.d. (Reel 34, Box-folder 27: 25)
  - "Pribićevići,", n.d. (Reel 34, Box-folder 27: 26)
  - "Proglas,", n.d. (Reel 34, Box-folder 27: 27)
  - "Report on the Voice of America,", n.d. (Box-folder 27: 28, Reel 34)
    Typescript. Includes Serbo-Croatian translation
  - "Report on Yugoslavia,", n.d. (Box-folder 27: 29, Reel 34)
  - "Robni Promet i Transport,", n.d. (Reel 34, Box-folder 27: 30)
    Typescript and handwritten draft (in Serbo-Croatian)
  - "A Science Against Man and People," (Reel 34, Box-folder 27: 31)
    Typescript with annotations
  - "Scientific Socialism,", n.d. (Box-folder 27: 32, Reel 34)
  - "Srbija,", n.d. (Box-folder 27: 33, Reel 34)
  - "Srpski Duh od Kosova do Ravne Gore,", n.d. (Box-folder 27: 34, Reel 34)
    Galley proof (in Serbo-Croatian)
  - "Street Mobs and Soviet Foreign Policy," (Box-folder 27: 35, Reel 34)
  - "Sumrak Jedne Ideologije,", n.d. (Reel 34, Box-folder 27: 36)
    Typewritten drafts with annotations (in Serbo-Croatian)
  - "Svoj Braći,", n.d. (Box-folder 27: 37, Reel 34)
  - "Swansong,", n.d. (Reel 34, Box-folder 27: 38)
  - "Tout va très bien, Madame la Marquise!", n.d. (Box-folder 27: 39, Reel 34)
    Notes, drafts, and typescripts
  - "U.S. and the U.S.S.R.: Theory of the Short Telegram," (Box-folder 28: 1-2, Reel 35)
  - Untitled fragments and writings
    - Communism (Reel 35, Box-folder 28: 3)
    - Russia and the Soviet Union (Reel 35, Box-folder 28: 4)
    - Vishinskii, Andrei (Reel 35-36, Box-folder 28: 5-6)
  - "Vaskrse Hristos, Srpski Narode!", n.d. (Reel 36, Box-folder 28: 7)
  - "Yugoslav Agriculture Today,", n.d. (Box-folder 28: 8, Reel 36)
  - "Yugoslavia,", n.d. (Box-folder 28: 9, Reel 36)
  - "Yugoslavia: Policy of the West,", n.d. (Box-folder 28: 10, Reel 36)
  - "What Are the Balkans,", n.d. (Box-folder 28: 11, Reel 36)
  - "What Is New From Moscow,", n.d. (Box-folder 28: 12, Reel 36)
  - "Danubian Peasant Parties,"., 1947 (Box-folder 29: 1, Reel 36)
    Includes letter to the editor of Economist. Holograph and typescript
  - Speech, Oxford University Philhellenic Society,., June 14, 1948 (Box-folder 29: 2, Reel 36)
    Includes letter from the secretary of the Society. Typescript
  - "Narodni Put," Glas Kanadskih Srba,., 1949 January 6 (Reel 36, Box-folder 29: 3)
    Printed copy
  - "Jugoslovenska Vojska Van Otadžbine," Oslobodjenje,., 1949 February 19 (Reel 36, Box-folder 29: 4)
    Typescript and printed copy
  - "Podaci o Garašaninu,"., 1949 May 12 (Reel 36, Box-folder 29: 5)
    Typescript. In Serbo-Croatian
  - Letter to the editor of Time and Tide,., July 16, 1949 (Reel 36, Box-folder 29: 6)
  - "Today's Yugoslavia,"., August 28, 1950 (Reel 36, Box-folder 29: 7)
    Joint memorandum by the Croatian Peasant Party and Serbian Peasant Party. Two versions, one titled "Yugoslavia, Annex to the Memorandum of the International Peasant Union to the United Nations General Assembly." Typescript
  - "Mihailović,"., 1951 (Reel 36, Box-folder 29: 8)
  - "A Federated Europe,"., 1951 February 26 (Reel 36, Box-folder 29: 9)
  - "Samozvanac i Njegova Laž,"., 1951 July 5 (Box-folder 29: 10, Reel 36)
    Draft and printed copy
  - Speech on Serbian Day, Windsor, Ontario, Canada,., July 5, 1951 (Box-folder 29: 11, Reel 36)
  - "Molotov on Tito,"., 1951 July 23 (Box-folder 29: 12, Reel 36)
  - "United States and Soviet Union,"., 1951 August 5 (Box-folder 29: 13, Reel 36)
  - "Yugoslavia in 1952,". (Box-folder 29: 14, Reel 36)
  - Speech, Women's Club, Middlesborough,., 1952 January (Box-folder 29: 15, Reel 36)
  - "Some Comments on American Policy Towards Tito,"., 1952 January/February (Box-folder 29: 16, Reel 36)
  - "Politika Zapada,"., 1952 May 15 (Box-folder 29: 17, Reel 36)
    Typescript and printed copy (in Serbo-Croatian)
  - "Coerced Federation,"., 1952 July 8 (Box-folder 29: 18, Reel 36)